We are building the next frontier of AI, which is what we call spatial intelligence. As in X, we are developing what we call a real to seem to real pipeline. We can replace all the data or the evaluation we need in the real environment by using the data that can generate at a scalable way in our digital world. Think about human intelligence. We do a lot of simulation in our head.
you know, why? There's a very important role simulation plays that real-world data doesn't play, which is counterfactual, reasonably. What we are building is a consistent world, consistent both over space, over time, over different viewpoints and over different type of interactions. My North Star is I want the real-world to work. The world we live in can be multiverse, that we create technology to allow
people, builders, developers to act within different spaces. Do you believe we'll ever be able to build robots that have the power efficiency of a human being? How far away are we from this? Is this like five years or this is like never? The TLDR is... Language models transformed how AI understands words. The next frontier is teaching AI to understand and act within the physical world. Following World Lab's acquisition of Cinex.
Martin Casato sits down with Fei-Fei Li and Yun Zhu Li to unpack the vision behind the deal. They discuss spatial intelligence, world models, simulation, and why solving robotics will require a new generation of AI, built for three-dimensional reasoning, not just language. All right, well, it's great to have you both here. So Fei-Fei, for the listeners that may not have the background, maybe you can give an overview of what World Labs does.
Yeah, well, World Lab is a two-year-old startup. I think we should just recognize it's a frontier model lab. We are building the next frontier of AI, which is what we call spatial intelligence. And spatial intelligence is about creating AI that has the ability to generate, understand, reason with, and interact with spaces, whether it's physical or virtual.
And of course, a means to an end towards spatial intelligence is building large world models. And that's what World Labs is mostly focused on. Yeah. So you've been saying this since the very beginning, which is the machine's ability to perceive and reason about spaces and act on spaces. But.
I always had the assumption that the acting on spaces was some long-distance huge thing, but now you're acquiring a robotics company. And so maybe talk a little bit about the timeliness of this and the intentions. Yeah. So first of all, it doesn't just take robotics to act within spaces or to interact, right? I mean, look at the creative field.
whether it's VFX or gaming or design, many use cases, you can create and act within virtual spaces. A world-lapse thesis has always been that the world we live in can be multiverse, that we create technology to allow people, builders, developers to act within different spaces. Having said that, the ability to act within the physical space is one of the most exciting and most
profoundly important capability of the future AI world. So robotics is very much that. So World Lab has always believed that robotics is an important application as well as use case of spatial intelligence and world modeling.
by joining force with inviting Cinex and Cinex team to our labs is part of our long-term vision and vision. We've always committed to that. Amazing. So Yunchu, you're the co-founder of Cinex. So maybe provide everyone with a quick overview of your background and what Cinex does.
Yeah, so I'm Yunchu, so I'm currently co-founder of Cinex and also assistant professor at Columbia University. So my research started from my PhD at MIT and then post-doc with FAA. Really? Yes. The world is small. The world is small. Throughout my career, my goal has been very simple. Trying to help the robots better perceive and interact with the physical world. So I'm a very practical person. I want my robot to work in the real physical environments.
So for Cinex, the unique opportunity we see is that there has been a lot of bottlenecks. Right now we see faced by the development of general purpose robots, especially around training and also around evaluations. So at Cinex, we are developing what we call a real to seem to real pipeline. We're going to map the real environments into the digital world that has the best alignments with the real environments.
By alignment we mean that whatever happens in the digital world is also going to happen in the real environment such that we can replace all the data or the evaluation we need in the real environment by using the data that can generate at a scalable way in our digital world. So that is how everything started in Cinex. We put together a very very strong and best teams around robotics, robot learning and also simulation and rendering trying to build this real-to-sint to real stack to solve some of the key bottlenecks.
It's amazing that you two work together. Yeah, and there is a funny story here because you would think because we work together, he was my amazing poster. We've been talking about this Cinex and World Lab integration for a long time. It's actually not true. They came into World Labs as a customer. Really? We released the first version of our generative model called Marble last winter around November, December. Cinex just signed up.
No kidding as a customer. Yes. And I didn't even know what it was. And then I realized this is Windrush company. I called Windrush, I'm like, wow, this is your company. And then we realized there's so much synergy. Maybe, Safie, just quickly describe what Marble is. Yeah, Marble is the code name for the base model that WorldLab is being training and iterating on the fundamental capability right now.
of marble that is publicly released is to take a prompt. It can be an image, it can be a few images or a text and turn that into a geometrically consistent world that can be represented in 3D geometry, whether it's Gaussian splat or mesh. Really what Cinex team is doing is trying to solve this extremely difficult problem in robotics, which is the lack of data.
The lack of data in training, lack of data in evaluation, this is very, very different from language models where data is abundant on the internet. And we know that in order for robotics to work, we have to somehow unlock the power of scaling law. But where does that come from? This is something that is a profound problem that everybody is battling with in robotics. It'd actually be great to talk about this energy.
put together a very very talented team. You have put together a very talented team. And so to what extent is there overlap to what extent is this an extension? Maybe talk a little bit about that. Yeah, that's how complimentary it is. It's actually the TLDR is very complimentary and with the shared mission. So Rindu is one of the three technical co-founders, the other two are Chang Xizhen, another Columbia professor who has been a world-class
technologist in simulation. And Changsha has his background in also VFX. He worked at Weta. He worked at Tencent. He is being an entrepreneur. Then there's Sunny Hu, who is a phenomenal engineering leader who was also in a startup that was acquired by Amazon many years ago. So he worked in many different tech stacks in the computer vision field in Amazon. So when we started talking more seriously,
I recognize that a couple of things that Cinex has from a talent point of view is extremely complementary to world labs. One is obviously in Drew's incredible thought leadership and just technical prowess in robotics, right? So from really...
from hardware full stack robotics. And even when he was my postdoc at Stanford, at that time you already had your faculty offer. So you were there only for one year. I wanted you for more than one year, but he had to go become a have the real job. So he was a full stack researcher in robotics from modeling to hardware. And of course, Indru and his students as Cinex was
that pull of talent World Lab hasn't had yet. Then on the Changsha side is just incredible simulation capability, right? He's such a senior researcher and technologist in simulation. And what World Lab is doing is very much interfacing the world of simulation. So I think what they don't have
obviously is on the generative model side as well as the computer vision 3d reconstruction side. We're also very strong at world labs. So that's a technology that's in its needs. So together these these two sides come together and make it much more complete. J-phase motivation in this is like this is an extension and a complement to get into robotics.
Having been in your situation, which is deciding when to sell a company would be great to hear from you and how you think about joining world labs and kind of the fit there and why you made the decision to do it. Yeah, so at the very beginning we were deciding, okay, do we want to just keep going? But after chatting with Fifei, after seeing all the synergies that are happening in the middle, it just makes perfect sense for the forces to join each other. So in any sense, as Cynics, what we have been doing is real to seem too real. It's to do dense reconstruction of the environment.
So we capture the appearance of the environment, geometry of the environment, and also the dynamics of the environment, meaning how the environment is going to change when you apply actions. So this dense reconstruction right now is still a little bit on the heavier side. And what World Labs right now has been doing involves a lot of profound capabilities around sparse reconstruction and generations.
So we see a lot of opportunities of leveraging like a marble and other like capabilities as world labs in order to do very efficient reconstructions and modeling of the environment. So can we expect a foundation model for robotics from world labs? World Lab is building the foundation model. As you know, Martin, we're building a base model. And as the technology has been evolving, some of the most exciting base models are omnimodals.
Right, they take multi-modal input, they have multi-modal outputs. And what is a foundation model for robotics? It's very likely going to involve actions. It's very likely going to involve the output of actions in addition to the state of the world. And we're definitely not ruling this out. Yeah, great. So for example, for the foundation models, it essentially needs to be a multi-modal model.
So it has to take into account frame text, image, depth, and different kind of modalities. And action is a very, very important part of that modality. So if you think about frame actions as an input, that is essentially a forward simulate. That is going to predict how the environment is going to change when you apply a specific action. When the action is out-of-field, this is essentially a policy model. That is trying to predict, give a specific goal, like what should be the action you take in the real environment to get you closer to that goal.
So these kind of omni models actually can benefit a lot and actually provide huge amount of values for the robotics communities in trying to understand how to model the environments and at the same time how to act in the environments. And this can also act as a backbone for you to find you into specific robotic applications to making sure it's really live up to the reliability and efficiency that expected by the clients.
You know, Yunxi, if you don't mind a kind of a lay investor question, I see a lot of robotics companies. And a very popular approach right now for the robotics companies that come in is like, we'll use a video model, you know, and like, you know, that's the predominant method where this is, you know, 3D and simulation, it's a very different approach. And so maybe you could contrast, you know, this popular approach of just using video only versus kind of what the ambition here is.
So in order to create words with a robot calendar, the words, as I mentioned, need to capture the essential structure of the problem. And one of the very important necessary requirements for those words will be consistency. So that is where I actually see very strong synergies with marble, because what we are building is a consistent word.
consistent both over space, over time, over different viewpoints, and over different type of interactions. And marble, the generated words from marble, is also provides an infrastructure, a component of that entire world that we believe is necessary for the robot tunnel. Imagine if a robot is pushing an object forward, the object just magically disappears, which has been a problem on many of the existing video prediction models. This one provides good enough signal for the robot to know what is the right thing to do.
But obviously right now there has been a lot of investigation on building better and better and stronger and stronger video models. So we actually see a way where some of the infrastructure rebuilds can provide as initial momentum and to go into this data flywheel of going from this more simulation driven models into like a robot policy models which are going to do the execution in the real environment.
connecting new data, the data will come back in, where the model doesn't necessarily have to be physics-only or learning-only, but somewhere in the middle, which should be able to capture the essential structure of the problem, but at the same time, be able to scale and become better and better as you accumulate more data. You know, I've worked now, say, very closely for a while, and...
And you've always had this North Star, which has driven this. And you've articulated variously as kind of 3D and in a number of other ways. And I'm just wondering, for you, is there also a similar philosophical North Star or you're more of the pragmatic like I am. I build the system, like do the thing. My North Star is to make robots work in the real environment. I'm a very practical person. I want the robot to work. Why is there something that's actually coming from my collaborations with Fifi during that postdoc?
We are building this kind of benchmark. We actually send out surveys asking the general public what they want the robots to do for them. Among the southern tasks we collected, one-third of the tasks are about clean. People just don't like to do those like a dull and dirty tasks. And those are the scenarios we really want to make sure we have robotic solutions to deal with. One thing I really like about Cinex, Martin especially,
Continuing your question, there's a lot of robotics companies building models and all that. One thing I truly like about Cinex is, is Rindu and his co-founders have such an incredibly pragmatic approach to robotics. They, especially they come from academia, right? Sunny doesn't, but Rindu and Chanxi come from academia, but their first instinct is work with design partners and customers in real.
industry, whether it's labs at industry labs or warehouses or electronics assembly. That is such a refreshing way of approaching robotics and that really made me very excited to work with them.
Maybe this is for you and you, but I just believe this is personal curiosity, which is it seems to me that for robotics you have to be pretty exact. I mean, not perfect, but pretty close. But for the creative use cases, which Rolex has done a lot of, you kind of don't need to because, you know, I mean, even sometimes like being wrong is stylistic or intentional or whatever. And so from a technical perspective, what is the challenge here for reconciling these two things? Or do they never get reconciled? Like, there'll always be two points in the design space.
So they will be like, reconciled in the long-term, of course. And modeling of the environments doesn't have to be perfect. The model doesn't have to be perfect in robotics. And by the way, this is pure curiosity, but is there like a bit more formal way to say that? Like, what does that mean not to be perfect? That's to be pretty close.
So let me put it this way. For example, models over the development of all different kind of robotic applications has been a very important cornerstone. If you look at all the existing robotic applications, like plane, drones, Roomba, or even for quadruped robots, bipedal robots, model has been the way for them to actually work and be able to transfer from simulation to the real environment. But if you look at those locomotion robots, like quadruped robots, bipedal robots, they can work on snows, they can work on bushes.
But you don't need to have a simulator. You can simulate all the bushes and snows very precisely. You need to have a simulation that captures the essential structure of the problem and do whole different kinds of randomizations inside the digital environment. So that is what we're aiming for. So basically, we're synics and together with word labs, we're trying to investigate what is the level of fidelity we need to model the massimax world besides the robots.
We'll be able to transfer the robotic systems training the simulated environment and digital worlds back into the real scenarios. As an investor, I've heard other researchers say like Sergey Lavigne say simulation will always eventually deviate from the physical world and real world data collection is absolutely critical. And so maybe talk a little bit about like the viability of this approach where simulation is a cornerstone as opposed to some other approach.
So they don't contradict with each other. So if you think about the simulation, simulation is essentially trying to predict how the environment is going to change when you apply the actions. And this is essentially a model of the world that doesn't necessarily have to be pure physics. It can be a combination between both physics and also learning.
We are collecting real-world data. We will be using those real-world data. It's just at different stages of this like a data flywheel. Maybe at the very beginning, we have stronger emphasize on we have more Phoenix to making sure we have the right consistency and right structure for us to know the the the world for us to train the robot policies. But as we accumulate more and more data both through data collection and also through the collaboration with our clients, we'll have the data that will be moving towards more towards
more learning based like modeling of the environments. So this kind of transition and also this kind of data flyer is really an enabling factors of both getting the best of both physics and geometry and consistency as well as all the power and magics from the data and compute. I want to add to this and be slightly philosophical here is there isn't a
binary choice between simulation or no simulation. All this come in together to make robotics work. Think about human intelligence. We do a lot of simulation in our head. You know, why? There's a very important role simulation plays that real world data doesn't play, which is counterfactual reasoning. Is that you play out events that can
It hasn't happened or cannot happen or you don't have enough data to make it happen in real world. And while you play it out, you learn how to act in it. Humans do this all the time. We probably don't, you know, we just, I know you were at World Cups. Congratulations to Spain winning. I'm sure in the planning of every game.
there is simulation, whether it's digital or on the whiteboard or whatever, that simulation, the role simulation plays is counterfactual reasoning. And that's really important in robotics because we just do not have, cannot possibly have enough real-world data for that. Here's a real-life example, the industry of self-driving cars. Weibo has officially said they use billions of hours of simulation.
And actually Waymo is more simulation heavy than just real-world data heavy. So these are real examples. And as you know, Martin and Inju too, cars are the simplest kind of robots. So clearly, simulation plays a huge role in robotic learning. I also want to add to that. So like they are, if you push things more specific, simulation can provide two levels of benefits.
The first one is reliability and the second one is efficiency. So for reliability, if you're thinking about a robotic system working reliable in the real environments, you need data to provide systematic coverage of all the state space and variations that robots might encounter. That's how you can learn about how that is robust. So with simulation, you can do systematic randomizations and control
and variations of lighting, frictions, geometries, object types, and also all different kinds of physical parameters to making sure you have sufficient coverage of the state space. So this is what can give the robotic system reliability. And second is about efficiency. So right now, many people are doing teleoperation. And if you look at many of the teleoperations device imagining all the actual skeletons you are using, you are actually collecting the data.
at a speed that is actually slower than humans actually doing the task. But for many of our clients, human speed to them is not good enough. They want faster than human speeds. So for the robot to move faster, it's not as simple as just driving the robot faster, because gravity doesn't change. But in simulation, you can do systematic speed-up of the robot's behaviors to train the robots such that it considers all the dynamics changes of the environment. So this is what can give our clients for them efficiency.
So both for the reliability and efficiency, there are some kind of like a very unique like values where simulation can provide. You've talked about the technology and the platform, what it does. Maybe talk about the specific use cases people use it for. There are essential like two specific use cases, especially around both training and also around evaluations. Starting from the evaluations. So evaluation is something like people often overlooked in the robotics.
But if you are training like rewarding models, you have to know how well it works and that is the only source of information for you to iterate. By the way, a lot of every AI person really understands what devals are and uses it all the time. Non-AI people, it often means something a little different. So maybe it's even worth just describing specifically what you mean by evaluation. Okay. So what I mean by evaluation is you'll be able to understand for this specific checkpoint, how well does it perform?
Does it perform for example 95% of the time or 99.9% of the time? And the key criteria people use in industry is how long does it take? How long in work clock time does it take for you to distinguish between a checkpoints that is 90% from a checkpoints that is 92 points? And if you only do that in the real environment, let's just take solar for you to do the distinguishments.
And if you really think about also the robotic evaluations right now people are doing in the real environments, the iteration speeds is multiple orders of magnitude slower than iterations of those language models. So not only is like the robotic
tasks very varied very diverse oh yeah like you actually have to do the thing yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah right like atoms have to move through space yeah but only there the laws of physics have to be updated right yeah right yeah watch those robotics videos every video has like 10x 8x because it moves so slowly exactly so not only slow it's dangerous it's costly but at the same time the speeds is also like a multiple hours of magnitude like slower so
Some of our clients actually need this digital environment that can be used to evaluate their robotic systems. And because our digital environment has proven alignments with the real world, meaning whatever happens in the scene is also likely to happen in the real environment. If a checkpoint is working better in the simulation, it's also highly likely to also work better in the real environment, as we have also been discussed in the blog post. So that actually gives our clients very strong confidence.
It's actually using the data using the signal from the digital environment to do scalable, safe, and much faster evaluations of their robotic systems. Great. So that is under evaluation. Then under training. So on the training sites, so basically like I also mentioned, it's about controllability. So you want to control all the different possible variations of states.
parameters, lighting, frictions, physical parameters, like even object geometry, object types. So you want to making sure you have sufficient coverage of all different kind of scenarios such that we will be able to generate like informative data for your robots to be robust. And this is just gonna be so hard to do just in the real environments. Like we discussed, if you do teleoperations, the speed at which you are collecting data is slow, you're also limited by like how many robots you have, how many teleoperations device you have. There's like a whole
different kind of like challenges around all the data operations around it. But in simulation, everything can be controllable, everything can be systematic, and everything can be understood at a level where you know exactly and making claims about exactly what distribution you have covered. To develop confidence about within the distribution, we know the robot will work.
So those kind of confidence and efficiency and scalability is something that our clients also value to use our digital words for the training of robotic systems. Here's the crazy thing. Even before Cinex and we are talking, our inbound customers for Marble were already seeing this kind of demands. We just cannot serve these customers, but we are already getting a lot of phone calls from robotics.
Early stage robotics companies were developing their models all the way to downstream very pragmatic use cases and we're seeing these these needs. When people hear you're going into robotics, what they're going to envision is you're pulling out a 3d printer and you're going to be making hardware and then you're going to be programming the brain of a robot and sticking it in the robot and then you've got a robot.
And I don't think that's what you guys are talking about here. So maybe talk about where this fits in the life cycle of creating a robot and where you will end and where the rest of the ecosystem will begin. So what we have been building, you can imagine, is infrastructure. Like with the softwares around these infrastructures for people to build wards such that robots can learn and evaluate. And this infrastructure is naturally
Model agnostic and embodiments agnostic. So I just want to be very clear just because this actually a very subtle if it is obvious, but this is very subtle point which is From what you said that's not building a robot. It's building an environment Which another company can place their robot brain exactly to navigate and to learn yeah, so for
Our customers right now, they have all different kind of robots. Some are using single robot arms, some are using bimeo, some are using a fixed arm, some are using mobile manipulators, some are using grippers, some are using some more elaborate versions of the only factors. So our platform right now is just naturally embodiment agnostic.
we can very easily integrate different kind of robotic embodiments, be able to put them into the words we generated, we digitalized, such that we will be able to give those individual robots capabilities of doing the right tasks and at the right levels of reliability and efficiency in the real environments. And we are also, for example, model-organistic. So we can just using the data generated by our words to train different models either from scratch or doing post-training of existing foundation models.
Vision language action models or word action models. So to us, it doesn't matter. We just want to making sure we have the infrastructure. We have all the words. So I say as the robot can work reliable in the real environment. You know, you have told me that you think a lot of the predictions around humanoid were a little bit aggressive and were likely to see more constrained rollouts like warehouses or whatever. Can you talk a little bit about that and like how that impacts what you're going to be tackling here at
like world labs. So that's a very good question. So if you look at, for example, all the progressions of robotic applications in the real environments, it has always followed the trend going from fully structured environments into semi-structured environments and then into unstructured environments.
For fully structured environments, what do we mean is that you have knowledge and control over all the configurations within the environment. Like factories. Like factories or for example car manufacturing lines. Those have been automated for decades. And then you have for example semi structured environments, which you have certain controls over the environments. For example like the Amazon warehouses or for example like restaurants, hotels where you have certain control over the environment to just make the task easier.
But there are obviously many other like objects or for example clothes, those are the objects you don't have control. And then for the unstructured environments, it's like your home and my home. Those is, I would say, the grand challenge. Especially my house, trust me, $3, 5 year old. Yes, dogs. Exactly. If you're thinking about where does robustness come from? Robustness comes from a sufficient coverage of the scenarios and robots might encounter.
So it's so much easier and more approachable at least like right now to focus more on the semi-structured environments before we move on to fully unstructured environments. So we will move into that direction. It just we want to take a more sustainable and more realistic approach towards them. I think your point here is that humanoid mimics human body and evolution has optimized human body for unstructured environment. And so our
Fingers, our legs are not the best apparatus to do one thing. For example, if our only goal as a species is to climb trees, we will not have this body necessarily, right? So we'll have different kind of fingers. But what humans end up having or evolved into is this body shape that can be very general, but not necessarily best at everything.
And that is for the survival of unstructured environment. But from a business point of view, from a pragmatic technology point of view, that this unstructured environment and a generalized body is actually the hardest problem to solve. It's not necessarily even the right way to solve the problem. We specialize, so we take more specialized body to solve.
a narrower problem. But the challenge for Cinex is that to be more body agnostic so that their infrastructure can serve different bodies and different semi-structured environments. A common lens to look at exactly this question is an economic lens, right? Which is, you compare it to like generative LLMs, where they can create a pros or a code.
10,000 times faster than a human being, a bunch cheaper than a human being. So the economic case makes sense because our brains aren't very efficient at that. However, our brains and our bodies are very efficient at 3D navigation, right? You know, like moving through the world or picking things up. And so this is just a prediction question, but do you believe we'll ever be able to build robots, at least in the foreseeable future?
that have the power efficiency of a human being when it comes to menial tasks. So let's say just basically minimum wage or something like that. Like how far away are we from this? Is this like five years or this is like never? I think it's gonna take a very long time. So if you really think about robots in real environments, in the end it will always be a system. So every working robot in the real environment is a system work.
it's new need to be very mindful and thoughtful about how the system are coming together. The hardware, the software, the brain, even like to the details of for example, what's the friction coefficients of your fingers. So there's a lot of things you have to consider to make these things a reality. And it will take iterations. But what I am excited about is that I've always been at the state of the arts of robot learning and also trying to push the state of the art forward. But the state of the art's always moving faster.
than I expected. So what I'm focusing on and trying to investigate right now is very different from when I started my PhD. So this is a speak to how fast the
whole ecosystem has been evolving and all the moving pieces are coming together or building these robotic systems. But we also have to be calibrated about our predictions. So we will see a lot of progress. But to achieve, for example, human level efficiency and capabilities, it will take longer. Martin, the hardest thing in today's AI is to have the right measured optimism.
Right. It's totally true. Yeah. I mean, even LLMs does not have human brain efficiency. Human brain operates on 30 watts. Yeah, that's true. That's so we are far from that. But I mean, performance to power it may be close, right? In narrow tasks like software engineering. Like generating an image or software engineering, that it is, right? Yeah.
I think so. I don't think we're anywhere close to the industrial products. This has changed how you think about your like strategically the level of ambition that your team can go after. I mean, does it, is it changed that or is it still very much in line with what you expected to do when you started? It definitely changed though to actually using a very profound manners. So we see a lot of unlock in being able to do this whole process through the modeling of the environments. You are much more efficient and much more scalable manners, especially in
partner together with the world labs. And I also want to add to Fei Fei, if you think about, for example, the current states of the language models, so those are models that's with incredible capabilities. But still you don't just blunt trust it to book your flight tickets or make your hotel reservations. You still, hopefully there's still a person who's reading the output from those language models. But that is very different from how people and we'll be using, for example, robotic models, based on robotic models out of the box.
the robot has to work reliably in the real environment. So, and we don't even have the data. We don't even have all the necessary infrastructures around those for the robots to just out of the box work reliable in the real environment. So for that reasons, be able to create these digital words, these scalable digital words where the robot can learn and evaluate within. This is going to unlock so much more potentials for being able to replace all the
like a costly and unsafe data in the real environments with the data generated from the words for the robots to be able to do scalable learning and evaluations. You know, I've seen many of these kind of integrations. They actually work very well at this stage when they have this much alignment, which is great. But there's always this question of, do you integrate now into what's happening now? Or do you keep things quite separate and provide kind of like a long-term trajectory that will, you know...
be realized in the year time frame. How are you thinking about this Fei Fei? Is this something that integrates right away or is this kind of a separate longer term? This is a great question. I think at this point, you know, Yundru, Chanxi, Sunny, Justin, Ben and I have been talking about this. At this point, we are going to take it thoughtfully. We're not rushing to integrate.
everything from code base to teams because I think Cygnus does have a very well thought and I wouldn't call it standalone completely but fairly contained a tech stack as well as their customers as well as the kind of products they're building. We're going to take time. We definitely will.
We already have a simulation side as well as the potential base model action condition model side. We already are starting to talk. And also they are using Marvel as an internal customer. So we will be integrating, but we're not rushing to blend the team as like for salad bowl. How are you thinking about geographies with this? With the C-next move, is it going to stay in the same place?
We're gonna, Vindra is gonna move. Oh, well, welcome. Here. I'm moving to San Francisco. Yeah, Florence to the Renaissance. Perfect. I think we, our labs is officially becoming a bi-coastal company where the headquarters is in San Francisco. I've, you know, I live in Palo Alto. I feel like I'm in the first day. But we, but I'm actually excited.
that we're going to have an office in New York that can help us to attract talent on the East Coast. And also we have been talking about making sure that in both offices we set up the robots so that we get to
Basically test out and mature our engineering stack so that we can work with robots remotely because we have to do that for our customers anyway. So maybe just to be very concrete, Fei-Fei, maybe let's just pencil out like what is the perfect success case in two years? Like what product do you have? Who's engaging with it? How do they use it? Just the crisp like what this becomes. I would be very happy that Cynyx team, World Labs team,
will have validated customers in a small number of important vertical use cases where our system, our infrastructure has proven to be truly beneficial to their automation needs. And these customers became our lighthouse examples to scale our business.
Now, how early, let's say someone listening to this is running a robotics company. At what stage do they engage with world labs? Is it really early on? Is it somewhere in the middle? So right now, for our customers, because we are building this kind of real-to-seem-to-real pipeline, where the simulation is essentially the worst, we're going to provide the treatment evaluation grounds. Some customers, they need only the real-to-seem part.
they want to digitalize the target care about and be able to do the evaluations of their robotic systems. Some customers need this real to seem to this entire pipeline such that they will be able to have policies running on their hardware. So our platform is also designed in a way that is flexible, depending on what our clients needs. And at the same time, the clients we are working with are actually pretty close to the deployment stage. So basically,
they are working on very very practical tasks. Those tasks when replaced, when we have a robotic solutions that are there, can just create value immediately. And they have like at least like tons or hundreds of like this kind of situations, they are thinking about to do the automations for. So as
like together with WordNaps, we'll be able to develop reliable solutions for those scenarios as we have already showed that we have a number of scenarios already instantiated in our blog post and we'll be able to further our investigation to see how they can actually solve the key like go like go.
requirements and also constraints faced by the real-world deployments. Great. I want to be very specific about this. Is it ever too late or too early to call World Labs if you're a robotics company? No, we want everybody to call us. We want to know about your use case. Wonderful. If you're listening to this and you're anywhere close to a robotics project or a robotics company, please track World Labs. Yes, thank you.
Definitely open for business. We're open for business. Not too early. All right. If you're doing robotics at 12 World Labs, thank you both very much for coming. Thank you. Thanks for listening to this episode of the A16Z podcast. If you like this episode, be sure to like, comment, subscribe, leave us a rating or review, and share it with your friends and family. For more episodes, go to YouTube, Apple Podcast, and Spotify. Follow us on X and A16Z,
and subscribe to our sub-stack at a16z.substack.com. Thanks again for listening and I'll see you in the next episode. As a reminder, the content here is for informational purposes only. Should not be taken as legal business, tax, or investment advice, or be used to evaluate any investment or security and is not directed at any investors or potential investors in any A16Z fund. Please note that A16Z and its affiliates may also maintain investments in the companies discussed in this podcast. For more details, including a link to our investments,
please see a16z.com forward slash disclosures.